Qing Yang TAN

Email: tanqingyang@u.nus.edu

Github: https://github.com/gingyan

Github: https://github.com/qingyangtan

Mobile: +65 9678 7183 Skype: qingyangt

Website: https://qingyangtan.github.io/Resume



Personal Statement

About Me

I am a Year 3 Business Analytics undergraduate at National University of Singapore (NUS). I am **fluent in Java, Python and R** and love developing algorithms to uncover new insights. At the age of six, I love dismantling items to understand the underlying components required for the product to function. That satisfies my curiosity. With big data, it fuels the same curiosity when I dive deep into the different layers of data to find an answer to a yet unknown question.

I am currently looking for a year-long internship in the data science field to experience the different stages of the data pipeline and apply school-based knowledge to the real-world problems.

Internship Experiences

StarHub Intern (Telecommunication company based in Singapore)

Upon completing the first year of study in NUS, I was amazed with what programming can offer. Excitedly, I embarked on my first internship at StarHub in the data analytics department. It was there when I experienced that the working world does not offer the same cushioning as the school environment does. I was tasked to complete a project in which I had no prior knowledge – Scala (Programming language) and Apache Spark framework. Being fresh to SQL, I had to apply queries which had been briefly taught at school. Nonetheless, I **enjoyed the challenge**. A part of me loved the exploration abounded with obstacles as each hiccup became a learning point.

The key takeaways from this internship were **adaptability** and **independent learning**. Using the resource that I had - Google, I was able to puzzle pieces of information from the Internet and sieve out the pertinent ones. With that skill, I was able to complete the given task in the shortest time with minimal guidance. While that may seem trivial, it was a personal turning point where I learnt to pick up new and foreign knowledge at an accelerated speed.

Schneider Electric Intern (French Multinational Corporation specializing in energy management)

I took every internship as an opportunity to improve myself in all dimensions. As such, with this second internship, I sought to place more emphasis on honing my **communication skills**. From the beginning, I established an open communication channel with my mentor where we had weekly exchanges on my work progress. With this establishment, I could make timely adjustments based on the feedbacks and built a zonal marketing dashboard (Tableau Software) way in advance of the internship's requirement. To maximize my learning at Schneider Electric, I requested for additional tasks in which I had the opportunity to render assistance in the automation of data load with Microsoft SQL (SSIS) as well as VBA scripting for Microsoft Excel.

How Can I Value Add?

Besides possessing strong technical foundation, I will be able to complement my knowledge with an ability to help your company design and use technology in a strategic way. With a forward-thinking mind, I can bridge the tasks on-hand with an optimized solution while keeping the business objectives at the forefront line of focus. Holding up this balance, I will be able to participate constructively, and communicate my ideas and suggestions. Packed with my internship experiences, I strongly believe I can promptly get familiar with your company's technology stack and start contributing by the end of the first week. As part of my belief, I will always put my best foot forward. I will **do my utmost best to help your company achieve the business objectives.**

**7 1		•	
Work	EXI	perienc	e:

Work Experience		
Jun 2017 – Aug 2017	 Schneider Electric Business Analyst Intern Building zonal marketing dashboard with Tableau Automation of data load with Microsoft SQL, SSIS VBA scripting 	Singapore
Jun 2016 – Aug 2016	 StarHub Business Analyst Intern Unit testing with python locust ETL with Apache Spark, using Scala language 	Singapore
Project		
Aug 2016 – Nov 2016	 The Coca Cola Company (TCCC) Analytics Report Webscraping to collect users' comments from Amazon, Twitter and YouTube Using wordcloud and sentiment analysis, the success or shortcomings of TCCC were identified 	
Education		
Aug 2015 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Business Analytics (Course details in Appendix A)	Singapore
Scholastic Achievemen	ts/Extracurricular Activities	
Aug 2016 - Present	IPREP Scholarship Infocomm Media Development Authority of Singapore (IMDA)	
June 2016	SAS Certified Visual Business Exploration and Design Using SAS Visual Analytics	
June 2016	School Contribution	

• NUS School of Computing Freshmen Social Camp Committee

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java	Proficient
8	Python	Proficient
	Ŕ	Proficient
	JavaScript	Intermediate
	Scala	Basic
Data Analysis Tools	R Studio	Proficient
	Tableau	Proficient
	SAS	Intermediate
	Matlab	Basic
Data Library (Python)	Pandas	Proficient
	Scikit-learn	Proficient
Database	MongoDB	Intermediate
	MySQL DBMS	Intermediate
	MS SQL	Intermediate
Framework	MeteorJS	Intermediate
	Apache Spark	Basic
Web Scraping	CasperJS	Proficient
	BeautifulSoup	Basic
	Scrapy	Basic
Web Development	HTML, CSS	Proficient

Language Proficiency

Spoken	English Mandarin	Fluent Fluent
Written	English Mandarin	Competent Competent

Degree: Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Business Analytics

Cumulative Average Point: 4.28 / 5.00

Course Type	Course Description	Grades
	E-Business Essentials	A
	Principles of Economics	A
	Principles of Marketing	A
Business	Business and Technical Communication	B+
	Financial Accounting	S
	Strategic Applications	S
	IS Innovations in Organization and Society	In-progress
	Introduction to Business Analytics	A-
	Application Systems Development for Business Analytics	B+
Business Analytics	IT Decision Making	B+
	Business Analytics Capstone Project	In-progress
	Computation Methods for Business Analytics	In-progress
Computing	Programming Methodology	S
	Data Structures and Algorithms I	B+
	Data Structures and Algorithms II	B+
	Machine Learning	In-progress
Mathematics	Calculus for Computing	B+
	Linear Algebra I	B+
	Probability and Statistics	B+
	Regression Analysis	B+
	Operations Research I	In-progress
Others	Economic Issues in Developed World	A
	Critical Thinking in the Information Age	B+
	Quantitative Reasoning	B+
	Real Estate Development and Investment Law	S

NUS Grading Scale:

 $A+\ \&\ A\ (5.0);\ A-\ (4.5);\ B+\ (4.0);\ B\ (3.5);\ B-\ (3.0);\ C+\ (2.5);\ C\ (2.0);\ D+\ (1.5);\ D\ (1.0);\ F\ (0)$

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn

Testimonial: StarHub





11th Aug 2017

Reena Agrawal Business Partner — BI Solutions East Asia Japan, IPO Schneider Electric

To Whom It May Concern,

Reg: Qing Yang Tan — Letter of recommendation

I am happy to provide this referral letter for Qing Yang Tan, a student of National University of Singapore, who was an intern in my team from 8 May 2017 to 11 Aug 2017, as a Business Intelligence Analyst.

Qing Yang exhibited a passion for learning and experimentation. He demonstrated the ability to quickly ramp up on new technologies and update his skills to align with the project needs. He displayed balance of excellent programming ability with optimal business acumen.

As part of his internship, he was tasked with building a zonal Marketing Dashboard to provide KPIs and metrics for business decisions. To accomplish this, he used a combination of tools and technologies — Excel Macros for Data transformation and Tableau Desktop for Visualizations. He also implemented MS SQL Server Integration Services package for data load for another project.

Qing Yang was able to accomplish his tasks in a timely manner and with minimal guidance.

It has been a pleasure to be his mentor, and I am confident that he will be a strong asset for future teams.

Regards,

Reena Agrawal

Schneider Electric

10 Ang Mo Kio Street 65 #02-01, TechPoint Building Singapore 569059 Phone: + 65 6480 2635

Commence of the same of the sa